Data often tells a story.
数据经常讲述一个故事
And often, a good plot can really help reveal what that story is.
通常 一个好的情节可以真正帮助揭示这个故事是什么
Now I'd like to show you how I think about these position
现在我想向你们展示我的思路 通过这些位置
versus time graphs to figure out the story the data tells.
与时间关系线图 找出数据背后的故事
Here, we have two axes.
在这里 我们有两个轴
In this case, time is the horizontal X axis and position is the vertical Y axis.
在本例中 时间是水平的 X 轴 位置是垂直的 Y 轴
And to begin, let's start with the simplest version
首先 让我们从最简单的版本开始
of our story by adding two data points,
增加两个数据点
one for a starting position of 30 miles at 2:00,
一个在 2 点 起始位置为 30 英里
and one for ending position of 80 miles at 3:00.
另外一个在 3 点 结束位置为 80 英里
Now, whenever I see data like this,
每当我看到这样的数据时
it's often helpful to imagine or even actually plot a line that connects the points,
假设或实际绘制一条线 把这些点连接起来 都会很有帮助
and this line represents where the car would have been at every moment between 2:00
这条线表示车辆在 2 点和 3 点之间的每个时刻的位置
and 3:00 if it were traveling at a single constant speed the whole time.
假设汽车一直以恒定的速度行驶
The line like this can be pretty helpful in making sense of these plots.
像这样的线可以很好地帮助理解这些绘图
Because once I have the line,
因为一旦我有了这条线
it's easier to see the change in position,
就能更容易看到位置的变化
or delta X, which is just the vertical separation between the two points.
或δX 这是两点之间的垂直间距
And change in time, or delta T,
以及时间的变化 或者δT
which is just the horizontal separation of these points.
这是这些点的水平间隔
And as you saw earlier,
正如你前面所看到的
you can also calculate average speed by dividing delta X by delta T. Now,
你也可以通过将δX除以δT来计算平均速度
I want to point something out that has some pretty profound implications for calculus.
我想说一些对微积分产生了深远影响的东西
The calculation of V average is
计算平均速度 V
the same calculation you would make to find the slope of this line.
与计算这条线的斜率一样
If you remember back to algebra,
如果你回溯到代数
slope is calculated as the vertical change in the graph divided by the horizontal change.
斜率被计算为图中的垂直变化值除以水平变化值
Or as I learned it, slope equals rise over run, which in this case,
或者据我所知 斜率等于 Y 轴坐标的距离差除以 X 坐标的距离差 在这种情况下
is delta X divided by delta T,
就是δX除以δT
so you can see that the slope of this line gives us
所以你可以看到 这条线的斜率表示
the average speed between these two points.
这两点之间的平均速度
And when the slope is steeper,
而当坡度较陡时
it means the average speed is faster.
这意味着平均速度更快
Now, we have to be careful to remember that this line is really just something we drew.
我们必须仔细地记住 这一行实际上是我们画的图形
It does not necessarily reflect where the car really was during the whole trip.
它并不一定反映整个行程中的真实情况
If we want to know a more complete story,
如果我们想知道更完整的故事
we're going to need more data.
我们需要更多数据
So, let's say we had sampled at 20-minute intervals and found that at 2:20,
所以 假设我们每隔 20 分钟抽样一次 发现在 2:20
the odometer read 40, and at 2: 40, it read 70.
里程表读数为 40 在 2:40 读数为 70
Well, once again, I'm going to draw some lines to connect these dots.
好的 我将再画线来连接这些点
And now, remembering that the slope of the line between
而现在 记住这两点之间的线的斜率
any two points gives the average speed between those points,
表示这些点之间的平均速度
I immediately can see that here in the first 20 minutes,
马上就能看到 在这里的前 20 分钟
the car was on average going much slower than it
这辆车的平均速度
was in the next 20 minutes since the slope isn't nearly as steep.
要比接下来的 20 分钟慢得多 因为斜面几乎没有那么陡峭
Then, in the last 20 minutes,
然后 在过去的 20 分钟里
the car, on average,
该车的平均速度
was moving slow again,
又一次慢了下来
and this really helps make the story clearer.
这确实有助于使故事更清晰
And if I want an even better understanding,
如果我想要更好理解
I would need even more data sample with an even shorter time interval,
那么甚至需要更短的时间间隔 进行更多的数据采样
like every 10 minutes or 5 minutes.
例如每 10 分钟或 5 分钟
And with this much data,
而有了这么多的数据
we don't even really need the connecting lines as a visual cue.
我们甚至不需要连接线作为视觉提示
And now, I can see that the average speed appears
而现在 我可以看到平均速度貌似
to have been greatest between 2:30 and 2:35,
出现在 2:30 和 2:35 之间
and they know that because I can see that the slope is steepest here,
因为可以看到 斜坡在这里最陡
which just means that delta X over delta T is greatest here.
这只是意味着在这里 δX 除以 δT 的值最大
And now, I like to give you a chance to interpret some graphs on your own.
现在 你可以自己尝试解释一些图表